<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Sethu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Sethu</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:43:39 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Section 1</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 12:35:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So then he tried to get the top part of his body out of the bed first,&#xA;carefully turning his head to the side. This he managed quite easily,&#xA;and despite its breadth and its weight, the bulk of his body eventually&#xA;followed slowly in the direction of the head.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review 1</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 10:48:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I’d forgotten myself so completely that I didn’t realise that if I don’t have peace of mind, I can’t help my child. That’s when I started sessions for myself as a mother. I came back to Sethu and booked a session with the therapist for myself. After some sessions I realised that to be there for my son 100%, I need to have my 100% first. I still sometimes struggle with this but with time I’m improving.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family Centered</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 09:09:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We prioritise the needs, values, and involvement of the entire family in decision-making and care, ensuring that interventions support not just the child but also their family system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Section 2</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 12:35:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But then he said to himself: “Before it strikes quarter past seven I’ll&#xA;definitely have to have got properly out of bed. And by then somebody&#xA;will have come round from work to ask what’s happened to me as well, as&#xA;they open up at work before seven o’clock.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review 2</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 10:48:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Pritam loves coming to Sethu. You’re always focused on his strengths, encouraging him in everything he does. That’s the best way for him to learn. He really appreciates it and so do all of us!”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— Juhi Prasad, guardian of Pritam, diagnosed with Down Syndrome in 2014&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengths Based</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 09:09:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We focus on identifying, building upon, and leveraging the existing skills, abilities, and resources of each child and their family to promote positive outcomes and growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Section 3</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 12:35:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Then the suitors came in and took their places on the benches and&#xA;seats.3 Forthwith men servants poured water over their hands, maids&#xA;went round with the bread-baskets, pages filled the mixing-bowls with&#xA;wine and water.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review 3</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 10:48:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I would look forward to my weekly sessions at Sethu throughout the week. It was the BEST time EVER – very comforting and homely. It’s amazing to just be there. Sethu has done a lot for me, I can’t imagine my life without it.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— Rucha Prabhudessai, screenwriter, diagnosed with dyslexia as a teenager.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neurodiversity Affirming</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 09:09:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We recognise, respect, and value neurological differences as natural variations of the human experience, while fostering an environment of acceptance and inclusion for all neurotypes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Section 4</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 12:35:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And Minerva answered, “I will tell you truly and particularly all about&#xA;it. I am Mentes, son of Anchialus, and I am King of the Taphians. I&#xA;have come here with my ship and crew, on a voyage to men of a foreign&#xA;tongue being bound for Temesa4 with a cargo of iron.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review 4</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 10:48:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Aditya was 11 when we met Dr Nandita by chance and explained why he had the habit of holding his breath underwater for extended periods. Not one doctor since he was 5 had been able to explain it. We went home and tried what she suggested and he was such a happy cookie. Next day we were at Sethu and have been like betaal behind Vikram ever since.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— Seema Sundaram, mother of Aditya, 23, who went on to acquire degrees from Linnaeus University, Sweden, and Brunel University, London, and become an internationally certified game ranger, open water diver and author in the making.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review 5</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 10:48:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“(Sethu works in a) systematic way with children, their parents, families, schools and teachers so that children grow up in an environment where they’re accepted and loved for who they are and what they have to offer the world. We’ve been touched by the passion and commitment of the Sethu team. We know many people who have been very happy to have volunteered at Sethu.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— Ligia and Jaime da Fonseca, Sethu donors&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review 6</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 10:49:04 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Ojas was diagnosed with autism as an infant but we didn’t want to accept the diagnosis at the time. Many doctors and elders told us he’d start speaking any day. But eventually we realised it wasn’t going to happen. He used to be very hyper. He’s calmed down a lot because of the therapy. He’s very excited about coming here.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— Prashant Rajput, uncle of Ojas, 12.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Positive Behaviour Support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/positive-behaviour-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:43:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/positive-behaviour-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developmental and learning disabilities can overwhelm children and adolescents, leading them to react in ways that are labelled ‘bad’ or ‘naughty’, when these are often just signs of unfulfilled needs. Our support plans account for the environmental factors influencing a child&amp;rsquo;s behaviour, as well the purpose which the behaviour serves. Behaviour support plans include modifying the child&amp;rsquo;s environment, including parenting, and we coach families to encourage, motivate and spark joy in children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Positive Behaviour Support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ehat-we-do/services/interventions/positive-behaviour-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:43:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ehat-we-do/services/interventions/positive-behaviour-support/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counselling and Psychotherapy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/counselling-and-psychotherapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:38:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/counselling-and-psychotherapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Mental Health team supports children, adolescents up till the age of 19 years for a range of concerns around anxiety, self-esteem, bullying and other learning, emotional and behavioural difficulties in complete confidentiality. We counsel parents individually and through family intervention sessions on effective parenting through healthy communication, understanding and responding to emotions and promoting parental mental wellbeing. Our use of narrative therapy is respectful, non-blaming and a collaborative approach to support the young people we work with to understand their problems, and develop healthy perspectives, experiences and actions. Therapy sessions with children and/or parents may be short- or long-term depending on the support required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/special-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:37:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/special-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our special educators help children who need support with academic learning, such as with reading, writing, comprehension and numeracy to cope with their schoolwork. Online and in-person training for parents and teachers is conducted on a range of topics such as learning disabilities, building life skills (such as bathing, getting dressed, brushing hair and teeth), toilet training, introduction to disability and classroom management, and inclusive education.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speech and Language Therapy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/speech-and-language-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:37:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/speech-and-language-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our speech and language therapists support children with varied communication needs including autistic children, children with cerebral palsy or Down Syndrome as well. Children with limited verbal communication or non-speaking children are supported through AAC (Alternative &amp;amp; Augmentative Communication), such as AVAZ or other low tech options where they can communicate using pictures and/or written words.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Occupational Therapy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/occupational-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:37:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/occupational-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Occupational therapy helps children with physical, sensory and cognitive problems become more independent at self-care, school and play. We’re the only nonprofit in Goa to offer aqua therapy, with its many physical, social and emotional benefits. Our occupational therapists conduct a detailed assessment of the child’s needs, provide a comprehensive written and verbal report, devise treatment plans and home plans, and conduct individual sessions as required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autism Intervention</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/autism-intervention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:36:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/autism-intervention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At AATISH, our autism intervention programme, we use a variety of play-based as well as structured approaches to understand the interests, strengths and needs of autistic children. We create customised intervention plans for each child and coach families to support their children at home. Sethu is the only non-profit in India to offer the Social ABCs™ (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.socialabcs.ca&#34;&gt;www.socialabcs.ca&lt;/a&gt;) intervention for autistic toddlers. We also conduct group programmes, such as on fine motor development, feeding and social inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psycho-Educational Testing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/assessments/psycho-educational-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:32:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/assessments/psycho-educational-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Children with academic difficulties, such as subject comprehension, learning retention and poor reading, spelling, written expression and math skills can benefit from psycho-educational testing. After establishing a rapport with the child to put them at ease, we test their abstract reasoning, problem solving skills, memory and attention span, critical thinking and other areas that influence academic achievement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neurodevelopmental Assessments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/assessments/neurodevelopmental-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:32:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/assessments/neurodevelopmental-assessments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We assess the child’s development in the areas of communication, gross and fine motor function, cognition and learning, play, socio-emotional and self-help skills. We also assess the functioning of the brain, spinal cord, nerves and muscles, and review their hearing and vision reports. For school-going children with behaviour and learning concerns, we go over their schoolwork, a report from their teachers, and may visit the school to observe the child at work and play.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:12:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/team/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/annual-reports/2023-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:09:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/annual-reports/2023-2024/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/annual-reports/2022-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:09:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/annual-reports/2022-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/annual-reports/2021-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:09:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/annual-reports/2021-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:55:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/media/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inclusive Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/inclusive-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:55:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/inclusive-education/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gnyandeep</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/gnyandeep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:55:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/gnyandeep/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Health</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:54:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/mental-health/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aatish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/aatish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:54:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/aatish/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child Development Centre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/child-development-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:54:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/resources/child-development-centre/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child Protection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/our-policies/child-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:53:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/our-policies/child-protection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This policy consists of preventive strategies and proactive procedures to ensure the safety of all children under Sethu’s care. It gives clear guidelines to both our staff and professionals working at Sethu in how we can best create a safe space for all the children who visit our premises and also when we interact with children out in the field.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1S0nHSyNToSqy4zAMGI8Mc-i2NjdlzW3d/view?usp=drive_link&#34;&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1S0nHSyNToSqy4zAMGI8Mc-i2NjdlzW3d/view?usp=drive_link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non Discrimination and Equal Opportunities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/our-policies/non-discrimination-and-equal-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:52:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/our-policies/non-discrimination-and-equal-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A policy and commitment of SETHU that it does not discriminate on the basis of race, age, colour, gender, nationality, ethnicity, physical or mental disability, or religion.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1sC80KFZjObWTCChe5SekE9nC2khwx7GR/view?usp=drive_link&#34;&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1sC80KFZjObWTCChe5SekE9nC2khwx7GR/view?usp=drive_link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theory of Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/theory-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:48:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/theory-of-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sethu’s Theory of Change (ToC) is a strategic planning document, developed in collaboration with Andrea Rodricks and Dr Marzio Babille, to guide us on our five pathways to change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:47:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our research efforts centre on promoting inclusion and involves systematic programme planning, monitoring and evaluation, as well as undertaking research projects. . Our papers have been published in reputed peer-reviewed journals and presented at national and international conferences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Published papers:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Posters presented at conferences:&#xA;&amp;lt;Shenessa’s IDPAC presentation&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Nandu’s IDPAC poster&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Andre’s PEERS Poster at IDPAC&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Andre’s Social ABCs Poster at INSAR&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Mahera’s Social ABCs Poster at INSAR&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Anjali’s Anganwadi Poster at IDPAC&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advocacy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/advocacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:44:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/advocacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We advocate for the effective implementation of neurodiversity-affirming policies by fostering close relationships with schools, community groups and government agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to collaborating with government agencies and families to claim their rights such as UDID cards, disability certificates and social security benefits, we advocate for inclusion through radio, television, the press and digital media.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commemorative days such as World Disability Day, World Autism Day, Autistic Pride Day, Down Syndrome Day, World Mental Health Day and ADHD month are rich with opportunities to raise awareness. We’ve also been active participants at Purple Fest, India’s first-of-its-kind international festival of inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training and Outreach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/training-and-outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:43:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/training-and-outreach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;image 54&amp;gt;&#xA;Inculcating a culture of learning and evidence-based action by proactively engaging, collaborating with and building capacities through webinars, collaborative workshops and other training programmes, is a very important aspect of our work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;webinars-and-workshops&#34;&gt;Webinars and Workshops&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our training for families, teachers, students and other professionals is delivered through webinars and in-person collaborative workshops on a range of subjects, such as sexuality education, ADHD, behaviour and inclusion in school. They’re particularly powerful in that they share the lived experiences of parents who’ve experienced success in these areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trustees</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/trustees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/trustees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of Sethu&amp;rsquo;s strengths is its strong administration which follows the principles of sound management. The trust is administered by 5 trustees who work on a voluntary basis. The administrative team monitors all systems of management to ensure that team members adhere to proper planning and work schedules, accounting protocols are followed and excellence in service provision is achieved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/our-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:08:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/who-we-are/our-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005 by Dr Nandita de Souza, a developmental paediatrician, and five other champions for inclusion, Sethu was born of the conviction that all children, particularly the most vulnerable, must receive a fair chance to realise their potential.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our first professional team comprised Dr Nandita, Yogita Joshi, special educator, and Anjali Barretto, speech and language therapist. Our three founder trustees were Elvina Menezes, Ameeta Mascarenhas and Sneha Bhandare. The first time we opened doors, it was in a compact two-bedroom apartment generously offered by Eric Menezes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
