<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What-We-Does on Sethu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/</link>
    <description>Recent content in What-We-Does on Sethu</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:48:29 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Theory of Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/theory-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:48:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/theory-of-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sethu’s Theory of Change (ToC) is a strategic planning document, developed in collaboration with Andrea Rodricks and Dr Marzio Babille, to guide us on our five pathways to change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:47:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our research efforts centre on promoting inclusion and involves systematic programme planning, monitoring and evaluation, as well as undertaking research projects. . Our papers have been published in reputed peer-reviewed journals and presented at national and international conferences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Published papers:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Posters presented at conferences:&#xA;&amp;lt;Shenessa’s IDPAC presentation&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Nandu’s IDPAC poster&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Andre’s PEERS Poster at IDPAC&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Andre’s Social ABCs Poster at INSAR&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Mahera’s Social ABCs Poster at INSAR&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Anjali’s Anganwadi Poster at IDPAC&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advocacy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/advocacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:44:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/advocacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We advocate for the effective implementation of neurodiversity-affirming policies by fostering close relationships with schools, community groups and government agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to collaborating with government agencies and families to claim their rights such as UDID cards, disability certificates and social security benefits, we advocate for inclusion through radio, television, the press and digital media.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commemorative days such as World Disability Day, World Autism Day, Autistic Pride Day, Down Syndrome Day, World Mental Health Day and ADHD month are rich with opportunities to raise awareness. We’ve also been active participants at Purple Fest, India’s first-of-its-kind international festival of inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training and Outreach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/training-and-outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:43:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/training-and-outreach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;image 54&amp;gt;&#xA;Inculcating a culture of learning and evidence-based action by proactively engaging, collaborating with and building capacities through webinars, collaborative workshops and other training programmes, is a very important aspect of our work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;webinars-and-workshops&#34;&gt;Webinars and Workshops&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our training for families, teachers, students and other professionals is delivered through webinars and in-person collaborative workshops on a range of subjects, such as sexuality education, ADHD, behaviour and inclusion in school. They’re particularly powerful in that they share the lived experiences of parents who’ve experienced success in these areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
