<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interventions on Sethu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interventions on Sethu</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:43:39 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Positive Behaviour Support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/positive-behaviour-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:43:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/positive-behaviour-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developmental and learning disabilities can overwhelm children and adolescents, leading them to react in ways that are labelled ‘bad’ or ‘naughty’, when these are often just signs of unfulfilled needs. Our support plans account for the environmental factors influencing a child&amp;rsquo;s behaviour, as well the purpose which the behaviour serves. Behaviour support plans include modifying the child&amp;rsquo;s environment, including parenting, and we coach families to encourage, motivate and spark joy in children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counselling and Psychotherapy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/counselling-and-psychotherapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:38:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/counselling-and-psychotherapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Mental Health team supports children, adolescents up till the age of 19 years for a range of concerns around anxiety, self-esteem, bullying and other learning, emotional and behavioural difficulties in complete confidentiality. We counsel parents individually and through family intervention sessions on effective parenting through healthy communication, understanding and responding to emotions and promoting parental mental wellbeing. Our use of narrative therapy is respectful, non-blaming and a collaborative approach to support the young people we work with to understand their problems, and develop healthy perspectives, experiences and actions. Therapy sessions with children and/or parents may be short- or long-term depending on the support required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/special-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:37:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/special-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our special educators help children who need support with academic learning, such as with reading, writing, comprehension and numeracy to cope with their schoolwork. Online and in-person training for parents and teachers is conducted on a range of topics such as learning disabilities, building life skills (such as bathing, getting dressed, brushing hair and teeth), toilet training, introduction to disability and classroom management, and inclusive education.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speech and Language Therapy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/speech-and-language-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:37:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/speech-and-language-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our speech and language therapists support children with varied communication needs including autistic children, children with cerebral palsy or Down Syndrome as well. Children with limited verbal communication or non-speaking children are supported through AAC (Alternative &amp;amp; Augmentative Communication), such as AVAZ or other low tech options where they can communicate using pictures and/or written words.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Occupational Therapy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/occupational-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:37:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/occupational-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Occupational therapy helps children with physical, sensory and cognitive problems become more independent at self-care, school and play. We’re the only nonprofit in Goa to offer aqua therapy, with its many physical, social and emotional benefits. Our occupational therapists conduct a detailed assessment of the child’s needs, provide a comprehensive written and verbal report, devise treatment plans and home plans, and conduct individual sessions as required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autism Intervention</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/autism-intervention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:36:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-we-do/services/interventions/autism-intervention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At AATISH, our autism intervention programme, we use a variety of play-based as well as structured approaches to understand the interests, strengths and needs of autistic children. We create customised intervention plans for each child and coach families to support their children at home. Sethu is the only non-profit in India to offer the Social ABCs™ (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.socialabcs.ca&#34;&gt;www.socialabcs.ca&lt;/a&gt;) intervention for autistic toddlers. We also conduct group programmes, such as on fine motor development, feeding and social inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
